<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  ~ Copyright (c) 2008-2016 Haulmont. All rights reserved.
  ~ Use is subject to license terms, see http://www.cuba-platform.com/commercial-software-license for details.
  -->

<credits>

    <items>
        <item name="Adobe XMP Library For Java" web="http://www.adobe.com/devnet/xmp.html">
            <license><![CDATA[
                The BSD License
                Copyright (c) 2009, Adobe Systems Incorporated  All rights reserved.

                Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:

                * Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.

                * Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.

                * Neither the name of Adobe Systems Incorporated, nor the names of its contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this software without specific prior written permission.

                THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS "AS IS" AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANT ABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT OWNER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
                ]]>
            </license>
        </item>

        <item name="Apache CXF" web="http://cxf.apache.org/" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Apache James Mime4J" web="https://james.apache.org/mime4j" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Apache Lucene" web="http://lucene.apache.org/" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Apache OpenNLP Tools" web="https://opennlp.apache.org/" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Apache PDFBox" web="http://pdfbox.apache.org/" license="apache-2.0">
            <jar>pdfbox-.*</jar>
            <jar>fontbox-.*</jar>
            <jar>jempbox-.*</jar>
        </item>

        <item name="Apache SIS Utilities" web="http://sis.apache.org/index.html" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Apache Tika" web="http://tika.apache.org/" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Apache Web Services" web="https://ws.apache.org/" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Apache XMLBeans" web="http://xmlbeans.apache.org/" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Boilerpipe" web="https://code.google.com/p/boilerpipe/" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Bouncy Castle" web="http://www.bouncycastle.org/java.html">
            <license><![CDATA[
Copyright (c) 2000 - 2011 The Legion Of The Bouncy Castle (http://www.bouncycastle.org)

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
]]></license>
        </item>

        <item name="curvesapi" web="https://github.com/virtuald/curvesapi">
            <license><![CDATA[
                Copyright (c) 2005, Graph Builder
                All rights reserved.

                Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
                modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
                are met:

                -Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice,
                this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.

                -Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice,
                this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation
                and/or other materials provided with the distribution.

                -Neither the name of Graph Builder nor the names of its contributors may be
                used to endorse or promote products derived from this software without
                specific prior written permission.

                THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS "AS IS"
                AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE
                IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE
                DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT OWNER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE
                FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL
                DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR
                SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER
                CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY,
                OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE
                OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
                 ]]>
            </license>
        </item>

        <item name="Ehcache Core" web="http://www.ehcache.org/" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="GeoAPI" web="http://www.geoapi.org/">
            <license><![CDATA[
                GeoAPI - Java interfaces for OGC/ISO standards
                http://www.geoapi.org

                Copyright (C) 2003-2011 Open Geospatial Consortium, Inc.
                All Rights Reserved. http://www.opengeospatial.org/ogc/legal

                This OGC work (including software, documents, or other related items) is being
                provided by the copyright holders under the following license. By obtaining,
                using and/or copying this work, you (the licensee) agree that you have read,
                understood, and will comply with the following terms and conditions:

                Permission to use, copy, and modify this software and its documentation, with
                or without modification, for any purpose and without fee or royalty is hereby
                granted, provided that you include the following on ALL copies of the software
                and documentation or portions thereof, including modifications, that you make:

                   1. The full text of this NOTICE in a location viewable to users of the
                      redistributed or derivative work.
                   2. Notice of any changes or modifications to the OGC files, including the
                      date changes were made. (We recommend you provide URIs to the location
                      from which the code is derived.)

                THIS SOFTWARE AND DOCUMENTATION IS PROVIDED "AS IS," AND COPYRIGHT HOLDERS MAKE
                NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED
                TO, WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE OR THAT
                THE USE OF THE SOFTWARE OR DOCUMENTATION WILL NOT INFRINGE ANY THIRD PARTY
                PATENTS, COPYRIGHTS, TRADEMARKS OR OTHER RIGHTS.

                COPYRIGHT HOLDERS WILL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL OR
                CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF ANY USE OF THE SOFTWARE OR DOCUMENTATION.

                The name and trademarks of copyright holders may NOT be used in advertising or
                publicity pertaining to the software without specific, written prior permission.
                Title to copyright in this software and any associated documentation will at all
                times remain with copyright holders.
            ]]>
            </license>
        </item>

        <item name="IntelliJ IDEA Annotations" web="http://www.jetbrains.org" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Jackcess" web="https://sourceforge.net/projects/jackcess/files/jackcess/2.1.4/"
              license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Java Native Access (JNA)" web="https://github.com/java-native-access/jna" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Java UnRar" web="https://javalibs.com/artifact/com.github.junrar/junrar">
            <license><![CDATA[
                ******    *****   ******   UnRAR - free utility for RAR archives
                **   **  **   **  **   **  ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
                ******   *******  ******    License for use and distribution of
                **   **  **   **  **   **   ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
                **   **  **   **  **   **         FREE portable version
                ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

                The source code of UnRAR utility is freeware. This means:

                1. All copyrights to RAR and the utility UnRAR are exclusively
                owned by the author - Alexander Roshal.

                2. The UnRAR sources may be used in any software to handle RAR
                archives without limitations free of charge, but cannot be used
                to re-create the RAR compression algorithm, which is proprietary.
                Distribution of modified UnRAR sources in separate form or as a
                part of other software is permitted, provided that it is clearly
                stated in the documentation and source comments that the code may
                not be used to develop a RAR (WinRAR) compatible archiver.

                3. The UnRAR utility may be freely distributed. It is allowed
                to distribute UnRAR inside of other software packages.

                4. THE RAR ARCHIVER AND THE UnRAR UTILITY ARE DISTRIBUTED "AS IS".
                NO WARRANTY OF ANY KIND IS EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED.  YOU USE AT
                YOUR OWN RISK. THE AUTHOR WILL NOT BE LIABLE FOR DATA LOSS,
                DAMAGES, LOSS OF PROFITS OR ANY OTHER KIND OF LOSS WHILE USING
                OR MISUSING THIS SOFTWARE.

                5. Installing and using the UnRAR utility signifies acceptance of
                these terms and conditions of the license.

                6. If you don't agree with terms of the license you must remove
                UnRAR files from your storage devices and cease to use the
                utility.

                Thank you for your interest in RAR and UnRAR.
                ]]>
            </license>
        </item>

        <item name="JDOM" web="http://www.jdom.org">
            <license>
                <![CDATA[Copyright (C) 2000-2004 Jason Hunter & Brett McLaughlin.
All rights reserved.

Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
are met:

1. Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
   notice, this list of conditions, and the following disclaimer.

2. Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright
   notice, this list of conditions, and the disclaimer that follows
   these conditions in the documentation and/or other materials
   provided with the distribution.

3. The name "JDOM" must not be used to endorse or promote products
   derived from this software without prior written permission.  For
   written permission, please contact <request_AT_jdom_DOT_org>.

4. Products derived from this software may not be called "JDOM", nor
   may "JDOM" appear in their name, without prior written permission
   from the JDOM Project Management <request_AT_jdom_DOT_org>.

In addition, we request (but do not require) that you include in the
end-user documentation provided with the redistribution and/or in the
software itself an acknowledgement equivalent to the following:
    "This product includes software developed by the
     JDOM Project (http://www.jdom.org/)."
Alternatively, the acknowledgment may be graphical using the logos
available at http://www.jdom.org/images/logos.

THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED ``AS IS'' AND ANY EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED
WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES
OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE
DISCLAIMED.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE JDOM AUTHORS OR THE PROJECT
CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL,
SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT
LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF
USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND
ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY,
OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT
OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF
SUCH DAMAGE.

This software consists of voluntary contributions made by many
individuals on behalf of the JDOM Project and was originally
created by Jason Hunter <jhunter_AT_jdom_DOT_org> and
Brett McLaughlin <brett_AT_jdom_DOT_org>.  For more information
on the JDOM Project, please see <http://www.jdom.org/>.
]]>
            </license>
        </item>

        <item name="Joda Time" web="http://www.joda.org/joda-time/" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Jsonic" web="http://jsonic.sourceforge.jp/" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Juniversalchardet" web="https://code.google.com/archive/p/juniversalchardet/" license="mpl-1.1"/>

        <item name="language-detector" web="https://github.com/optimaize/language-detector" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Java Libpst" web="https://github.com/rjohnsondev/java-libpst" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="JHighlight" web="https://github.com/codelibs/jhighlight" license="cddl-1.0"/>

        <item name="Maven SCM API" web="https://maven.apache.org/scm/maven-scm-api/" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="metadata-extractor" web="https://github.com/drewnoakes/metadata-extractor" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Morphology for Lucene" web="https://code.google.com/p/russianmorphology" license="apache-2.0"
              fork="true"/>

        <item name="MP4Parser" web="https://code.google.com/archive/p/mp4parser/" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="NetCDF Java" web="http://www.unidata.ucar.edu/software/thredds/current/netcdf-java">
            <license>
                <![CDATA[
Copyright 1998-2015 University Corporation for Atmospheric Research/Unidata

Portions of this software were developed by the Unidata Program at the University Corporation for Atmospheric Research.

Access and use of this software shall impose the following obligations and understandings on the user. The user is granted the right, without any fee or cost, to use, copy, modify, alter, enhance and distribute this software, and any derivative works thereof, and its supporting documentation for any purpose whatsoever, provided that this entire notice appears in all copies of the software, derivative works and supporting documentation.  Further, UCAR requests that the user credit UCAR/Unidata in any publications that result from the use of this software or in any product that includes this software. The names UCAR and/or Unidata, however, may not be used in any advertising or publicity to endorse or promote any products or commercial entity unless specific written permission is obtained from UCAR/Unidata. The user also understands that UCAR/Unidata is not obligated to provide the user with any support, consulting, training or assistance of any kind with regard to the use, operation and performance of this software nor to provide the user with any updates, revisions, new versions or "bug fixes."

THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY UCAR/UNIDATA "AS IS" AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL UCAR/UNIDATA BE LIABLE FOR ANY SPECIAL, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION, ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE ACCESS, USE OR PERFORMANCE OF THIS SOFTWARE.
]]>
            </license>
        </item>

        <item name="Ogg And Vorbis For Java" web="https://github.com/Gagravarr/VorbisJava" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Plexus Common Utilities" web="https://codehaus-plexus.github.io/plexus-utils/"
              license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Quartz Enterprise Job Scheduler" web="http://www.quartz-scheduler.org/overview/"
              license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="ROME" web="http://rometools.github.io/rome" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Sentiment Analysis Parser" web="https://github.com/USCDataScience/SentimentAnalysisParser"
              license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="StAX API" web="https://github.com/codehaus/stax" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="TagSoup" web="http://home.ccil.org/~cowan/tagsoup" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="Woodstox" web="https://github.com/codehaus/woodstox" license="apache-2.0"/>

        <item name="XZ for Java" web="https://tukaani.org/xz/java.html">
            <license><![CDATA[
            This Java implementation of XZ has been put into the public domain, thus you can do whatever you want with it. All the files in the package have been written by Lasse Collin, but some files are heavily based on public domain code written by Igor Pavlov.
            ]]></license>
        </item>

    </items>

    <licenses/>

</credits>